hey guys bre and ter here I've been
getting a couple of emails from people
who have purchased HP thrusters and
wanted to know about band
placement so uh I'll just go over what
we do here at glute lab so first of all
about the band themselves you can get
bands from
sorex from Elite FTS from Rogue uh
there's probably more compan out there
to sell them those are probably the main
three but this is the smallest band
these are from SX this is a monster mini
um if you buy it from Elite FTS it's red
but it's the smallest band and then you
have the light
band which is purple from SX you have
the average band which is green you have
the strong band which is blue and then
this is the Monster Band from SX thing
is huge but uh if you buy it from Elite
FTS I think they call it the pro strong
b anyway and this one's a lot more
expensive because of how thick it
is we
use uh the monster mini band for
beginners this is a perfect band for
beginners I'm not sure how much
resistance it offers but probably like
you know like say 30 30 lbs at the top
or
so once they can do you know like a
couple sets of 20 reps we will graduate
them to the light
band and a lot of female plants will use
the light band and the average band but
our stronger female clients I'll
actually use the strong
band um you can also use these with
single leg which I'll get to later but
with
the when I do hip thrust I will use
either the strong band or the Monster
Band I like to do two sets I like to use
both and the reason why I like to use
both is because when I use this I
actually use more range of motion at the
hips I push the hips higher and I really
feel it the problem is I can get like 30
reps with
this um and so then I'll use this and do
like 15
reps but I like doing both of them they
both work great when I do hip thrust I
like to do them off of the far
placement so here's the last band Peg
and I will just pull it over to the side
and hook it in like
this and then I'll P this Peg out so
then I get it I make sure it's even on
my hips and then I will get into place
from
here and then just like a regular hip
thrust just start thrusting
so with this one I'm going to push the
hips higher like that that and I end up
using more range of motion I do not come
down all the way to here I will stop
right about here this is where you start
getting tension so from here I just
go and this creates more constant
tension and
then I
will also use the monster B now this
one is crazy how much tension it
provides on the
glutes
um so this one's a little bit harder to
get
in cuz it's so
big but
uh this provides a ton of tension on the
glutes this one our strongest people use
so
here get
position and then
so when you do
this um it's kind of a this is this is
for our strongest
clients
um Andrew and Joey use this my friend
Mike uses this one guys who can you know
like squat 400 plus lbs and dead 500
plus pounds we'll typically use this
guy um the strongest women typically use
this but some of them can get like 30
reps with this still so I have had some
of the strongest women
combine these two
bands the uh average and the strong
bands but it's kind of like this they
don't quite get as much range of motion
at the hips now we also have been
experimenting
with putting the bands back further and
elevating the back further up kind of
like the American hip thrust with that I
do with the barbell but I'm going to
have Andrew demonstrate that but I
should mention I'm 6'4 and I will use
when I do American hip thrust I place it
one peg back because my back is further
up on the bench but I'm going to have
Andrew demonstrate that and then
um strong some people are very good at
single leg I'm not
I just use body weight for single leg or
sometimes I use this but Joey is really
strong with the single leg so he
uses um he actually uses this he's used
the strong band it's a little bit heavy
for him but he likes to use the average
band when he does sing leg so I'll have
him show
that I should also mention before I get
started with Andrew here is that a lot
of our female the shorter female clients
we have them uh this is the placement
they use the second Peg back that works
better for them and some of the medium
height women we will actually go like
this and wrap it around both pegs like
this but with uh Andrew here he's going
to do it just like this on the second
Peg because he's going to hinge from
higher up so if he were doing the
standard hip thrust he would hinge from
right here okay but he likes to come up
higher up on the bench so he's hinging
at the kind of like the mid back area
and then watch when he does this it
naturally lends itself towards posterior
pelvic tilt so Andrew likes this style
better I kind of like it better too but
I do both um anyway this way is good for
if people say like I feel these in the
low back you have them shift up higher
and you have them do that and they won't
feel in their low back anymore but that
I call the American version and all you
do is you just shift the bands back a
little bit because your back is shed J
higher on the
bench and now here's Joey he's really
strong at the single leg version so he
uses the the farthest placement he likes
to use the average band here to go for
it Joey here's him doing single
leg this is really hard for me to do
okay switch legs
some people are a lot stronger at single
leg some people are weaker at it and
some people like the single leg version
more than the double leg um I get a lot
more out of the double leg but I have a
lot of strong friends we like doing the
single egg work anyway that's how we use
the bands here in the glute lab we like
to do uh sometimes we'll do drop sets
where we will start like with the
Monster Band and move to the strong band
and then move to the average band with
women we will start with our strongest
female clients we'll start with this the
strong move to the average and then go
to the light band but uh we also have
been experimenting with um complexes so
you can do like some lateral band stuff
and then move right into the band hip
thrust and that gives you some extra
like metabolic stress and burn on the
glutes but anyway hopefully you can see
uh it's pretty basic pretty
straightforward with how to use the
bands with the hip Thruster um if you
don't have a hip Thruster you can do
this in a power act but it's really hard
to get the right you know with these
we've figured out the right distances
and we can be very systematic about it
but Power acts are all very different um
so I can't make broad recommendations
with different Power RS anyway I hope
you enjoy the video thanks for watching